

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211





Sayantan Sen Sterling Integrator specialist (IT Analyst) seeking role in Project Execution, Software Development, Root Cause Analysis, Client Engagement, Stakeholder Management, Requirement Gathering, Change Management, Software Development Life Cycle Current Designation: IT Analyst Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 1 Month(s) Current Company: Tata Consultancy Services Ltd. Notice Period: 3 Months Current Location: Kolkata Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers] Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Kolkata, Pune Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming / Maintenance Role: Project Lead Industry: IT-Software/Software Services Marital Status: Single/unmarried Key Skills: Sterling Integrator specialist, Project Lead, Project Execution, Software Development, Root Cause Analysis, Client Engagement, Stakeholder Management, Requirement Gathering, Change Management, Software Development Life Cycle. Putty. Eclipse. Unix Shell Script Verified : Le Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 19-Jan-21 Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

Jump to Section Work Experience | Education | IT Skills | Work Authorization

Summary

Proactive and achievement-oriented professional with over 5 years of experience in in the full software development process from concept through delivery of next generation applications and customizable solutions

Proficient in IBM Sterling integrator tool 5.2 and 6.0(Business Process, Map Editor, Code List, Web Service, Mailbox)

Understanding of Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC), right from requirement analysis, documentation (functional specifications, technical design), coding and testing (preparation of test cases along with implementation) to maintenance of proposed

Liaised with users for requirement gathering; prepared functional specifications and lowlevel design documents Interacted with team members to ensure smooth progress of project work; ensured adherence to quality norms throughout the implementation process

Work Experience

Tata Consultancy Services as IT Analyst Oct 2015 to Oct 2015

Growth Path:

Assistant System Engineer Trainee 2015-2016 Assistant System Engineer 2016-2017

System Engineer 2017-2019 IT Analyst Since 2019

Project Executed: Team Size: 3

Period: Jan'16-Present

Tools: Sterling Integrator, Oracle 10g/11g/12c/19c, Unix, Java, Python

Key Result Areas:

Engaging in Sterling Integrator Coding, analysis, development and performance tuning

Producing Maps, Business Process

Installing sterling integrator & upgrading its version

Sterling integrator version update

Troubleshooting the system related problems reported by production support team, QA

Creating a business process in Sterling Integrator, which reads data from csv files insert and update data in multiple configuration tables

Developing:

o Business processes, maps in order to deploy code from repository into the system o An automated deployment process using business process, Maps, shell scripts to deploy codes in another environments

o Code in python in order to compare codebase between two environments

annlication in sterling Integrator order to compare the code have between two

Important

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

environments

Coordinating with team members to ensure smooth progress of project work

Training & mentoring the new interns/trainees about the systems and software languages used in the project

Modifying various maps using Gentran Integration Suite/Sterling Integrator's Map editor Creating business process for both inbound and outbound transactions as per business needs using Graphical Process Modeler and BPML in Gentran Integration Suite/Sterling Integrator

Transforming BPML to handle document archiving, failure notifications, report generation and automated code base deployment

Tata Consultancy Services Ltd. as IT Analyst

Oct 2015 to Till Date

sterling integrator edi developer

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Future Institute of Engineering and Management, West Bengal University of Technology in 2015

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Las	st Used	Experience	
Windows 10, Windows 7	202	20	9 Year(s) 0 Mor	nth(s)
Red Hat Linux	202	20	5 Year(s) 1 Mor	nth(s)
IBM Sterling Integrator 5.2.6.3	202	20	5 Year(s) 1 Mor	nth(s)
Shell Scripting	202	20	4 Year(s) 0 Mor	nth(s)
Oracle 10g/11g/12c/19c, PL/SQL	202	20	5 Year(s) 0 Mor	nth(s)
Putty, Toad, HP Quality Centre, Eclipse	202	20	5 Year(s) 0 Mor	nth(s)
SOAP UI, Notepad +++, PyCharm	202	20	4 Year(s) 0 Mor	nth(s)
Jira, Confluence	202	20	2 Year(s) 0 Mor	nth(s)
Python 3.7, 3.8	202	20	1 Year(s) 1 Mor	nth(s)
Java 1.7, Java 1.8	20	19	3 Year(s)	

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
Hindi				
English				
Bengali				

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: **General**Physically Challenged: **No**

US Work Status: Need H1 Visa

Countries: India
Job Type: Permanent
Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.